《绿箭》上季回顾
Last season on "Arrow"...
帕尔默科技
值得吗
Was it worth it?
你从那岛上带回来的痛苦和不幸
All the pain and misery you brought back from that island?
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
我回来
The reason I came back
是为了拯救这座城市的市民
was to try and save the people of this city.
你们抓错人了
You've got the wrong guy.
翻译   Liv   SophiaSaaaga  冰蓝   沫沫
奥利弗·奎恩不是绿箭
Oliver Queen isn't the Arrow.
我才是
I am.
所有人都认为绿箭死了
Everyone thinks the Arrow is dead,
翻译    小暴徒   Silence   天青月白
也就是说奥利弗·奎恩是无辜的
which means Oliver Queen is innocent.
我加入联盟时  是和另一个人一起被征召的
When I joined the league I was conscripted with another man,
精校  陈小圈
达米恩·达克
Damien Darhk.
达米恩继续联盟的运作方式
Damien continues the League's ways,
但是通过他自己的组织  里面是一群特工
but through his own organization filled with a hive of agents.
时间轴 风吹来的那片云  校对  迷失_绽放  沫沫
约翰
John?
不对劲
Something's wrong.
首先我向你保证莱拉不会受到任何伤害
First, let me assure you that no harm will come to Lyla.
特效&后期   咖啡Lee   总监   苹果果
你不仅破坏了我们的友情
You didn't just... lose my friendship.
你还失去了我的信任  失去了我对你的尊重
You lost my trust. You lost my respect.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
我必须确保你们俩是安全的
It was about making sure that you and you were safe.
我只能让尽可能少的人知道这件事
I had to keep the circle as small as possible.
你打开了我的心扉
You... opened up my heart in a way
以一种我自己都觉得不可思议的方式
I didn't even know was possible.
我爱你
And I love you.
我能说句奇怪的话吗
Can I say something strange?
我很开心
I'm happy.
你好吗
How you doin'?
好吧
Oh. Ok.
费利西蒂·斯莫克
Felicity Smoak...
你的煎蛋饼失败了
You have failed this omelet.
真的吗
Really?
是啊
Yeah.
做饭对你来说那么容易  真是没天理
You know, it's criminal how easily cooking's come to you.
我一直想提升一下厨艺
Well, I always wanted to expand my horizons
因为我在那岛上能做的
beyond what I could do on the island,
基本上不是熟食就是生食了
which was basically... was cooked and uncooked.
慢跑怎么样
How was your jog?
挺好的
It was good.
我开始习惯不追着人跑了
I'm getting used to running without chasing after someone.
我身上有汗
Kind of sweaty.
我知道  很棒
I know. It's amazing.
怎么把这个纹身去掉了
Why'd you get this one removed?
我不需要了
I don't need it anymore.
你今天打算干什么
So what do you have planned for the rest of the day?
跟帕尔默科技董事会开视频会议
A video conference with the Palmer Tech board,
他们仍在质疑
who still question whether
我是否适合继承雷的遗产
I'm fit enough to inherit Ray's legacy.
我把公司还给你
Hey, how'd you like the company back
作为提前送你的圣诞礼物怎么样
as an early Christmas gift?
你经营公司比我做得好多了
You're doing a better job of running it than I would.
公司就要破产了[调情]
It's flirting with bankruptcy.
是啊  这就是调情
Exactly. This is flirting.
我得走了
I gotta go.
你现在去哪里
Where are you going now?
我得去农贸市场为明天的早午餐买东西
I have to get stuff at the Farmers Market for brunch tomorrow.
对了  霍夫曼夫妇要过来  我忘了
Right. The Hoffmans are coming over. I forgot.
制定的计划不包括有人会对我开枪
I'm never gonna get tired of making plans
这个我永远也不会厌烦的
that don't involve people shooting at me.
太酷了
This is so cool!
你对"酷"的定义真得改改了
We're really gonna have to work on your definition of cool.
让我上去
Get me up there.
这太棒了
This is so awesome!
科尔德实业
闪电妞  小心身后
Speedy, behind you!
我跟你们说了要叫我红箭
I thought I told you guys to call me Red Arrow.
红箭头意味着你不能左转
A red arrow just means you can't make a left turn.
随便了  我在被劫持的卡车里了
Whatever. I'm inside the hijacked truck.
金丝雀  该你了
Canary, you're up.
该死  他们有后援
Damn, they have backup.
绿 箭
第四季  第一集
有人看到被偷走的货物了吗
Anyone manage to get eyes on that stolen cargo?
看起来像是设备箱
They look like equipment containers.
不是设备  是武器
Not equipment. Weapons.
科尔德实业
科尔德实业是世界上
Among other things, Kord Industries
最大的军火制造商之一
is one of the largest arms manufacturers in the world.
他们还制造了很棒的手机
They also make a really awesome cell phone.
但更可能是武器
Yeah, but weapons are more likely.
很有可能
Much.
这些幽灵  如果我们真要这样称呼他们
These ghosts, if that's seriously what we're calling them,
他们正加紧攻击
are stepping up their attacks.
事态在升级
Escalating.
人们害怕极了  根本就不愿出门
People are so scared, they don't even want to leave their homes.
除非是在夜晚打包行李
Unless it's to pack up in the middle of the night,
逃离这地方
get the hell out of town.
你想让我们怎么做
What do you want us to do,
拿着橄榄球回家吗
take our football and go home?
不  我们寻求帮助
No. We ask for help.
奥利弗选择了离开
Oliver walked away.
那是在这些人开始接管城市
That was before these guys started taking over our city
把它变成战区之前
and turning it into a war zone.
我们是在应对危机
We're dealing with a crisis.
奥利弗相信我们能应付得来  劳蕾尔
Which Oliver believed we could handle, Laurel.
他是对的
And he was right.
星城
我昨晚跟沃尔特·斯蒂尔谈过了  他不干
I spoke to Walter Steele last night. He passed.
你觉得惊讶吗
Well, does that surprise you?
三年来  我们有三位市长  一位市长候选人
In 3 years we've had 3 mayors and one candidate
他们都死了
for mayor who've all ended up dead.
任何头脑正常的人
Anyone with any common sense
都不会想参加竞选
is not gonna throw their hat in the ring.
我们不能继续这样吗
Can't we just go on as we have,
让委员会来管理市政厅  就不用选市长了
running city hall by committee instead of electing a mayor?
也许你该集中精力抓住这些幽灵
Maybe we should have you focused on catching these ghosts.
那是媒体的叫法
That's just what the media calls them.
因为他们会像幽灵一样消失
Because they disappear like ghosts.
我没说这叫法不好
Yeah, I didn't say it wasn't cute.
事实上  这些人很难抓
The truth is, these guys are hard to catch.
他们不是一般的罪犯
They're not your average everyday criminals.
一般罪犯不会把氰化物胶囊塞在牙缝里
Average everyday criminals don't have cyanide capsules
宁愿把自己干掉  也不接受审问
in their teeth so they can off themselves rather than be interrogated.
我已经竭尽全力了
I'm doin' the best I can here.
我们需要你再努力点
We need you to do better.
这城市在各种面具男出来肆虐之前
This city was dying before more masks showed up
就在垂死挣扎了
to wreak havoc.
我们最终会抓住这些人  扭转局面的
Look, we'll get these guys eventually and things will turn around.
我们重塑了城市
I mean, look, we rebranded the city,
有了新的旅游计划
we got the new tourism program,
还有通往中城的高速铁路
we got the new high-speed rail line to Central City.
从中城开来  希望能成
Hopefully from Central City.
或许有朝一日我们也能像他们一样
Well, maybe we can have a Flash day,
有个"闪电侠"日
just like them.
重点是  我们需要增加大量人手
Bottom line, we need an influx of people,
也就意味着需要大量资金
which means an influx of cash.
不不  你们坐好
Oh, no, no. Keep your seats.
不好意思  这是秘密会议
Excuse me, this is a private meeting.
太好了
Oh, excellent.
我最讨厌被人打搅了
I despise interruptions.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
我吗  我就是你们要找的人
Me? I'm the man you're looking for.
我掌管那些...你们叫他们什么
I'm the one who controls-- what do you people call them?
幽灵
The Ghosts?
你们都在为这垂死的城市焦急万分
So you're all fretting about the city dying.
而我所代表的这个组织
I'm here on behalf of an organization
希望你们放任它死亡
that wants you to let it die.
死亡是件美好的事
See, death is a beautiful thing.
我们死后  回归大地
We die, we go into the ground,
我们遗骸的墓地长满鲜花
our remains grow into flowers.
只有在死亡之后  新的事物才能发芽
It's only in the interval after dying that new things can sprout.
够了
That's enough.
你给我滚出...
And now, get the hell out of--
城市就像小狗
Cities are like puppies.
看见它们在街头痛苦地扭动
You see them writhing in agony on the streets,
应该让它们死个痛快  而不是继续受折磨
you put them down. You don't let them suffer.
我去叫保安
I'm getting security.
苏珊娜  冷静点  坐下
Susanna, calm down. Get down.
这样非常无礼
That's very rude behavior.
你们看起来都不怎么招人爱
None of you seem particularly likeable,
但如果你们有任何朋友
but if you do have any friends
或是爱你们的人
or anyone who does love you,
还是尽早道别吧
I suggest you say goodbye.
我的人会和你们联系
My people will be in touch.
奥利弗
Oh, Oliver,
这鸡蛋太美味了
These eggs are heaven.
别告诉我你是用...
Don't tell me you made them--
是用慢炖锅  你送我们的慢炖锅
In the slow cooker. The slow cooker you got us, yeah.
我就知道  我就知道
Aww. I knew it. I knew it.
人们总是不愿意尝试它
People are always so hesitant to try them,
可慢炖锅绝对能改变生活
but slow cookers are absolute life-changers.
简直是真理  应该用作车尾贴的
I don't know how that is not a bumper sticker yet.
就是啊
I know.
说到改变生活
On the topic of life-changers,
你们真该开始考虑学校的问题了
you guys really need to get on the school situation here.
我们可以帮你们写封推荐信
We could write you a recommendation letter
上我们学校的等候名单
for our school's waiting list.
可是  不该先有几个孩子再说吗
But--but wouldn't it help to have kids first,
至少得有一个
or, I don't know, a kid?
上那个名单得等好几年呢
Oh, it takes years to get on that list.
而且你们俩肯定离生孩子不远了
And I'm sure kids aren't too far down the line for you two.
我们还没谈过这个
Yeah, we haven't talked about it.
谁要再来点含羞草鸡尾酒
Who wants more mimosas?
给我看看  你有带在身上吗
I need to see it. Do you have it on you?
别这样  宝贝
Shh, shh. Honey--
你有带着吧
You have it on you, right?
有吗
Do you have it?
太漂亮了
Oh, it's stunning.
是我母亲的
It's my mother's.
那你打算什么时候问那个问题
So, when are you gonna pop the question?
今晚
Tonight.
你们在说什...
What are you guys talking...
兄弟
Dude!
反应够快的啊
Nice reflexes!
五年前
别过来  疯子
Back off, psycho.
已经有六个人
6 people have died
被你的鬼把戏害死了
from the crank you've been pushing.
其中四个还是孩子
4 of them were kids!
你的爱好真是不同寻常  奎恩先生
You've certainly chosen an unusual hobby, Mr. Queen.
他说他会把我们全杀了
He said he'd kill us all.
这新闻发布会真够呛
That was a hell of a press conference.
应该好好提醒一下这帮人
These people needed a strong reminder
这城市不会向恐怖分子屈服
that the city doesn't bow to terrorists.
苏珊娜
Susanna?
我就觉得味道不对劲
I thought that tasted funny.
快报警
Call 911!
约翰  又有新问题了
John, we have a new problem.
城市领导被盯上了
The city's leadership is being targeted.
他们刚给地方检察官下药了
They just poisoned the District Attorney.
我这就去找我父亲
I'm headed to my father.
我需要你和西娅负责另外两名成员
I need you and Thea handle the other two members.
星城市政厅
我离紧急事务主任最近
I'm closest to the Head of Emergency Services.
西娅  我要你赶往市政厅
Thea, I need you at city hall.
你还好吗
Are you ok?
能派个护士过来吗
Can we get a nurse over here?
地方检察官刚倒下了
Hey, listen, the District Attorney just collapsed.
工作人员认为可能是中毒
Staffers think it might be poison.
我需要做毒理...
I need toxicology--
好了  好了  别开枪
All right, all right, all right, all right.
别激动
It's all right.
好了  好了  好了
All right, all right, all right, all right.
坚持住  我找人来帮忙
Just hold on. I'll get you some help.
你没事吧
You ok?
兰斯队长  你被警告过了
Captain Lance, you were warned.
你没事吧
Are you ok?
没事  一点皮肉伤
Oh, yeah, it's just a flesh wound.
兰斯队长
Captain Lance,
地方检察官已被宣布死亡
the District Attorney was pronounced dead,
并且有消息称  城市审计官
and reports are coming in that the City Comptroller
和紧急事务主任也已身亡
and the Head of Emergency Services have also been killed.
这基本是这城市的所有领导了
That's pretty much the city's leadership.
再这样下去  都没有城市需要领导了
Carries on like this, there won't be a city left to lead.
有什么大事吗
So what's the occasion?
得有大事才能吃晚餐吗
We need an occasion for dinner?
不是  自从你迷上了烹饪
No. Ever since you discovered cooking,
生活就成了播不完的"厨艺大师"
life's been a never-ending episode of "Master Chef."
但这不只是晚餐  这是个作品
But this isn't dinner. This is a production.
我们是要...
Are we...
庆祝什么吗
celebrating something?
那要看看甜点怎么样了
It sort of depends on how dessert goes.
不行  不行  我快要撑死了
Oh, no, no, no. I'm almost disgustingly full.
这个蛋奶酥  你一定要尝上一两口
You are going to have to try a bite or two of this souffle.
救命的门铃啊
Oh, diet saved by the bell.
怎么了
What's going on?
有人找你
You have visitors.
我们应该先打电话  但是...
We probably should have called first, but...
我们真的需要你帮忙
We really need your help.
媒体把他们称为"幽灵"
The media has been calling them The Ghosts.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
这些人是前所未见的
They're like nothing we'd ever seen before.
-训练有素  武器精良  -而且忠心不二
- Well-trained, well-armed. - And committed.
只要我们一接近他们其中一员
Anytime we get too close to one of them,
他们就会用氰化物自杀
they off themselves with cyanide.
他们的目标是什么
What's their agenda?
起初我们以为他们只是窃贼
At first we thought they were thieves
因为他们袭击的都是银行和珠宝行
because they were hitting banks and jewelry stores.
然后我们发现原来他们在累积战争基金
Then we found out that they'd just been building their war chest.
他们现在偷的都是军需品和重型武器
They've now been stealing munitions and heavy arms.
还进行暗杀活动
And assassinating people.
警方都干什么了
Where are the police?
被击垮了
Overwhelmed.
如此规模的组织
Well, a group of this size
一定会有一个核心位置
has to work out of a central location,
一个行动基地
a base of operations.
我们至今还没有找到
Which we haven't been able to find.
狄格似乎认为我们可以应付
Dig seems to think we can handle it.
你不同意吗
You disagree?
我觉得我们已经力不从心了
I think we're in over our heads.
我们需要绿箭
We need the Arrow.
绿箭已经死了
The Arrow's dead.
我们希望事实不是如此
We're hoping that's not the case.
我们希望你无法改变骨子里的本性
We're hoping that you can't change who you are in your bones.
来帮助我们阻止那些人
Come help us stop these guys,
然后你就可以回到你的...
and then you can come back to your--
蛋奶酥的平静家庭生活中
your domestic life of tranquility and souffles.
你怎么这么安静
You're uncharacteristically quiet.
我该说什么呢
What should I say?
我们的朋友需要帮助  我们早该上路了
Our friends need our help. We should already be in the car.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
像奥利弗·奎恩这样的人
The world's too small
想在这个小世界消失谈何容易
for someone like Oliver Queen to disappear.
说实话  我还以为会在星城找到你
Truth be told, I expected to find you in Starling City.
我不想离我的家人太近
I don't want to be near my family.
因为你对瑞孚做的那些事吗
Because of what you did to Shrieve?
我看了他的验尸报告
I read his autopsy report.
我虽然早知道你有深不可测的能力
I knew you had a capacity for the unfathomable,
但我还是低估你了
but I actually underestimated you.
你想怎么样  阿曼达
What do you want, Amanda?
想帮助你
To help you.
你一直不肯回家
You haven't returned home
就是因为你认为自己是个怪物
because you feel you're a monster.
你一直试图否认  想把你的杀戮本能
You're trying to deny it, channeling your killer instinct
转移到有用的事情上
into something productive.
但你无法改变你骨子里的天性
But you can't change who you are in your bones.
我不需要心理医生
I don't need a therapist.
兜帽和眼部装饰展示了你的那一面
The hood and eye makeup may suggest otherwise.
不要再试图逃离你内心的黑暗
Stop trying to run from your inner darkness.
拥抱它
Embrace it.
任其自然发展
Let it run its course.
通常情况下  离开的唯一方式就是通过
Oftentimes, the only way out is through.
通过什么
Through what?
超能力联合调查组
ARGUS agents.
你醒来时
When you wake up,
记住  我是想帮你
just remember that I'm trying to help you.
星    城
纪念雷蒙德·帕尔默博士重新命名
我以为像这样坐在豪车后座的日子
Here I thought that my days
已经一去不复返了
of riding in the back of limos was long gone.
当帕尔默科技代总裁的特权之一
One of the perks of being Palmer Technology's CEO in absentia.
现在我回来了  他们可能期望我真的做点什么
Now that I'm back, they might actually expect me to do stuff.
我不担心  我们不会待太久的
I wouldn't worry. We're not going to stay long.
看着窗外  让人很难不产生疑惑
It's tough not to look out this window with wonder.
疑惑什么
Wonder what?
我们究竟实现了些什么
What did we really accomplish?
费利西蒂和我有很多功课要补
Felicity and I have a lot to catch up on,
所以先让我们看一下目前收集到的证据
so maybe take us through all the evidence the team has gathered.
很简单  什么也没有
That's easy. Nothing.
好  那就让我们了解一下
Ok, so maybe we'll go through all the encounters
你们和幽灵交手的过程
that you've had with The Ghosts,
他们曾藏身的每个地方  你们能找到的...
everywhere they've hidden, and places you can cross...
约翰...
John...
我们应该先讨论一下
We should have discussed this.
西娅和我讨论过了
Thea and I did.
我们需要他
We need him.
我没指望你能敞开怀抱迎接我
I'm not expecting you to welcome me back with open arms.
我对你所做的事很难轻易被原谅
What I did to you is not easily forgiven.
我是来帮助你们解决困难
I'm here to help you with your problem,
然后我就走
and then I'm gone.
奥利弗  我们不需要你的帮助
Oliver, we don't need your help.
就算需要人帮忙  我们也会选择那些
And if we did, we'd probably choose someone
没有绑架我妻子和使我孩子犯险的人
who didn't kidnap my wife and endanger my child.
没有人要求你当做那些事没发生过
And no one is asking you to pretend like that didn't happen.
但我们有麻烦了  这城市有麻烦了
But we're in trouble. The city is in trouble.
劳蕾尔  你不需要提醒我
Laurel, I don't need you to remind me of that.
我就是没法跟我不信任的人一起作战
I just can't go into battle with a man I don't trust.
理解  不过事情比你们想得要恶劣得多
Understood. But things are a little worse than you guys thought.
我侵入了科尔德实业的电脑
I hacked into Kord Industrie's computers
想看看那些幽灵偷了些什么
just to see what The Ghosts stole.
集束炸弹  传感器引爆  波及范围大
Cluster bombs. Sensor fused and high yield.
比这个更强大的只有核武器
Any more powerful and they'd have to be nuclear.
你想怎么样  约翰
What do you want to do, John?
我要不惜一切代价拯救我的城市
I'm gonna do whatever it takes to save my city.
有武器  就有目标
Weapons need targets.
偷这些东西一定有原因
These had to be stolen for a reason.
费利西蒂  侵入科尔德实业的数据库
Felicity, hack into Kord Industry databases.
我要知道一切有关于这些爆炸物的信息
I want to know everything there is to know about these explosives.
劳蕾尔  联系一下你的父亲
Laurel, we want to start a dialogue with your father
列出潜在目标的名单
and make a list of potential targets.
狄格  西娅  去街上转转  看能发现什么
Dig, Thea, hit the streets, see what we can find.
抱歉
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
老习惯
Old habits.
给你父亲提个醒不是件坏事
It's probably not a bad idea to give your father a heads-up.
明白
Copy.
约翰
John, look--
我有妻子还有个学步的孩子要照顾
I have a wife and a toddler to get back home to.
费利西蒂  有发现了告诉我好吗
Felicity, will you let me know if you find anything?
会的  替我向莱拉问好
Will do. Say hi to Lyla for me.
他会想通的
He'll come around.
我去街上转转
I'll go hit the streets.
我得说用键盘干点别的
Well, I have to say it feels good to be at a keyboard
而不只是开远程会议真是太棒了
for something other than a teleconference.
我需要一张地图  所有幽灵袭击过的地点
I need a map with a list of all the spots the ghosts have hit,
包括他们跟组员交手的地方
including where they encountered the team.
如果幸运的话  也许还能...
And if we get lucky, maybe we can--
三角定位出幽灵
Triangulate and determine the point of origin
行动的基地  是吗
of where the ghosts are operating out of, yes?
好了  这是他们抢劫和袭击过的其他地方
All right, here's the rest of all their heists and attacks.
可真快
That was fast.
是吗  是啊  就像骑自行车一样
Yeah? Yeah, like riding a bike?
他们袭击的第一个地方是拉森信贷联盟吗
First spot they hit the Larson Credit Union?
不  那是星城国家银行
No, no, no. It was Starling National.
是吗
Yeah?
你是怎么知道的
How'd you know that?
跟你知道拉森的方法一样
Same way you knew about Larson.
费利西蒂
Felicity.
玩个游戏怎么样
Want to play a game?
什么游戏
What game am I playing?
这游戏叫
Playing the reason that you know
"你这么了解幽灵是因为
so much about Ghost is because you've been
你一直背着我帮他们"
helping the team behind my back game.
这帮人都开始用集束炸弹了吗
These guys have got cluster bombs now?
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
所以我才过来
Well, that's why I'm here,
问问你知不知道他们的潜在目标
to see if you're aware of any potential targets.
我只知道
The only thing that I'm aware of is that
我希望你离这场混乱越远越好
I want you to stay as far away from this mess as possible.
爸爸  我以为我们已经谈过这个了
Dad, I thought we'd moved past this.
很多事都已经过去了
We've moved past a lot of things,
我很开心  真的
and I am glad, really.
但我不想让你和这些疯子打交道
But I don't want you mixing it up with these psychos.
城市领导出了这样的事  你还这么想吗
Even after what happened to the city leadership?
我说真的
I mean, honestly.
我以为我们来帮忙你会很高兴呢
I thought that you would be happy to have our help.
你看我像高兴的样子吗
Do I look happy?
爸爸  幽灵还没开始用炸药的时候
Dad, the Ghosts were dangerous before
已经够危险的了
they got their hands on experimental explosives.
等他们炸掉一个街区  想到你没有去阻止
How are you gonna feel when they take out a city block,
你会作何感想
knowing you didn't do anything to stop it.
关于他们的目标
Have you heard of anything going on
你有听到什么风声吗
that's a potential target?
地标建筑  星城总院之类的吧
Landmarks, Starling General, etc.
有没有什么市级活动
What about city events?
有什么高官要来吗
Any dignitaries coming to town?
几场球赛  音乐会
A few ballgames, concerts.
估计也没人会去了
Not that there's anyone to buy a ticket.
明晚火车站会重新开放
Train station's getting reopened tomorrow night
因为那条新铁路
for that new rail line,
星城总院会发起一场罐装食品募捐
and Starling General is having a canned food drive.
没人会到星城来了  劳蕾尔
People don't come to Star City anymore, Laurel.
人们只想离开
They want to leave.
最可爱的是谁呀
Who is the cutest?
世界上最最可爱的是谁呀
Who is the cutest, ever, ever?
你这样陪她玩  你看是非你莫属了
Playing with her like that, I'm pretty sure it's you.
真神奇  什么都可以消失
It's amazing how everything else can just melt away
唯有她不行
except for her.
今晚有什么消失了
What's melting tonight?
我知道这几个月你挺辛苦的
I know it's been a rough few months.
要对付那些人
These men you're dealing with.
今晚就一个人
Tonight it's just one man.
奥利弗回来了
Oliver's back.
这么快就回来了
That didn't take long.
你知道他会回来
If you knew he was coming back,
怎么不提醒我一声
why didn't you warn me?
那句话怎么说来着
What's the saying?
"唯有死者见过战争的结束"
"Only the dead have seen the end of war."
奥利弗不是个战士
Oliver's not a soldier.
不是吗
Isn't he?
你还真是不记仇
That's pretty forgiving,
六个月前才被他绑架过
considering he kidnapped you 6 months ago.
你知道他为什么那么做
You know why he did.
你总要释怀的
You have to let go of it sometime.
我就已经释怀了
I have.
因为你比我好
That's because you're better than me.
这正是我爱你的原因之一
That's one of the reasons why I love you.
那是场战争  约翰
It was war, Johnny.
虽然要对付的不是一个国家
Maybe not against a country,
但仍是场战争
but it was war.
在战争时期  有时也身不由己
And in times of war, we do what we have to do.
是吗  莱拉
Really, Lyla?
包括对我撒谎吗
I mean, that include lying to me?
还有对费利西蒂撒谎
Lying to Felicity?
有必要吗
What was the point?
为了打败拉斯  奥利弗做了他认为必要的事
Oliver did what he thought he had to do to defeat Ra's.
我没说他的决定就是正确的
I'm not saying he made the right choice.
但如果奥利弗·奎恩的决定永远正确
But if Oliver Queen always made the right choice,
他就不需要你了
he wouldn't need you.
我以前觉得奥利弗大嗓门的时候很吓人
I used to think that yelling Oliver was scary.
现在觉得奥利弗不说话的时候更吓人
I'm starting to think that silent Oliver is a lot worse.
我在回想过去的五个月
I'm just going over the past 5 months in my head.
我们在泰国那阵  你食物中毒...
When you got food poisoning when we were in Thailand...
对  我可能确实一直偷偷帮他们
Yes. I might have been secretly working with the team,
但食物中毒不完全是骗你的
but I didn't exactly lie about the food poisoning.
泰式香辣猪肉确实很难消化
Laab moo is extremely hard to digest.
你在波西塔诺坐船误点那次呢
What about when you missed our boat, missed in Positano?
好吧  那次我确实撒了个小谎
Ok, that one was a little fib.
巴厘岛呢
Bali?
费利西蒂  你说巴厘岛根本收不到电邮
Felicity, you said there wasn't even email in Bali.
我知道
I know!
不过我有多厉害你是知道的
But we both know I'm just that good.
我不明白 我们要重新开始  就是为了
I don't understand. The whole point of starting over
远离这一切是非
was to get away from all of this,
我们去那里  就是为了新的开始
and we were both right there together leading that charge.
我知道  我也以为那就是我们需要的
I know. And I thought that's what we needed.
开始几个月确实很棒  非常棒
And the first few months were great, really great.
但是当你和劳拉·霍夫曼
But then when you and Laura Hoffman
开始交流厨艺
started exchanging cooking tips,
我都想把自己眼睛挖出来
I secretly wanted to gouge out my eyes.
我还以为你很开心
I thought you were happy.
我是很开心  和你在一起  我开心极了
I was. Deliriously happy with you,
但其余的一切都了无生趣
but bored with everything else.
我很想念这里
I missed this.
我想念拯救城市  帮助市民
I missed saving the city and helping people.
那给我的生活带来目标
It gives my life purpose.
我也很希望和你一样
And I wish I got the same thrill from picking
挑选餐具都觉得兴奋
between the dimpled flatware or the scalloped,
但我做不到
but I just don't.
我不在乎你对我撒谎
Hey. I don't care that you lied to me.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我在乎的是那段时光
I care that the entire time
我们本该一起远离这一切
we were supposed to be away together,
但你的心却还在这里
part of you was still here.
我爱和你在一起的每分每秒
I love every moment that I'm with you,
不管我们在哪里
no matter where we are.
那是什么
What's that?
我黑进了科尔德实业
I hacked Kord Industries to check
找他们的炸弹设计原理图
their design schematics for their bombs.
发现他们的炸弹里有定位追踪器
Turns out they have a GPS tracker built in.
能查到它的位置吗
Can you find out where it is?
至少能查到它去过的地方
At least where they've been.
定位器现在关了  去过的上一个地点是...
GPS is offline now, but their last location was...
阿德米拉运输交汇处
Admiral Transport Interchange.
是佩尼镇外一处货车停车场
It's a truck depot outside Pennytown.
两个月前停业了
Closed up shop two months ago.
我打给西娅  你联系劳蕾尔和狄格
I'll call Thea. You get Laurel and Dig.
正好这会儿可以告诉你
This might be a good time to tell you that Cisco
西斯科在知道你要离开前  做了点东西
worked up a little something before he knew you were leaving.
一套新装甲
A new suit.
我们很快就走  不需要新装甲
We're not staying long enough for a new suit.
阿德米拉运输交汇处
我听说过这样的地方
I heard about places like this.
城市走下坡路  业主就不干了
Owners must have left when the city started tanking.
看来我们的新朋友把它派上用场了
Well, our new friends seem to have found a use for it.
先生们  这个世界
Gentlemen, the world's a--
是个有趣的地方
it's a funny place.
它抵触改变
It resists change.
反抗进步
It fights progress.
因此  前进的唯一办法
And so the only way to move things forward
就是反击
is to fight back.
你们今天在这里  就是因为明白这一点
And you men are here today because you understand that.
但我们的队伍强大与否
But our cause is only as strong
取决于能力最弱的人
as our weakest man.
阿尔瓦雷斯先生  请向前一步
Mr. Alvarez, please step forward.
那天晚上  你指挥劫持
You commanded the hijacking the other night,
科尔德实业的集束炸弹
the cluster bombs from Kord Industries.
是的  我们遭到了抵抗
Yes, sir. We encountered some resistance,
但还是解决了
but we handled it.
解决
Hand--hand--
我想我对"解决"的理解
Well, I guess my definition of "Handled"
和你的有点不一样
is a little different than yours.
要知道  当我"解决"了一个问题
You see, when I "Handle" a problem,
问题就不存在了
the problem dies.
长官  我们带着炸弹离开
Sir, we got away with the bombs--
我喜欢这小城的秋天
You know, I love this town in the fall.
也许这里的秋天看起来
I mean, yes, it looks pretty much the same
和其他三个季节没什么不同
as it does in the other 3 seasons,
但我喜欢一致性
but I admire consistency.
我推崇可靠性
I respect dependability.
但这两样你都没展示出来
And you've shown me neither.
那么现在  让我给你展示点东西
So now, allow me to show you something.
另外一种美
It's another kind of beauty.
那就是对原始能力的操控
It's the manipulation of primordial energies.
不明白吗  太难了吗  好吧
No? Over your head? Yeah.
就是上帝撬动世界的杠杆留下的痕迹
The grazing of the levers that God uses to move the world.
还不明白
No? No?
就是这个
This.
我的天
Oh, my God.
那是什么
What the hell is that?
行动
Move!
闪电妞
Hey, Speedy!
星城警署  举起手来
SCPD! Put your hands in the air!
他们要用炸弹干什么
What are they gonna do with the explosives?
火车
Train...
告诉我
Tell me!
他们要摧毁星城火车站
They're gonna destroy Star City station.
把手举起来
Hands up in the air.
得走了
We got to go.
快走
我记得这种表情
Oh, I remember that look.
不是什么好事
That is not a good look.
至少我们知道了他们的企图
We found out what they had planned, at least.
他们要用炸弹摧毁新火车站
They're gonna use the explosives on the new train station.
这个可能我早就想到了
Ah, pretty sure I had that one in the office pool.
说得太早了吗
Too soon?
他们很有可能打算明晚袭击
They're probably planning the attack for tomorrow night,
在庆祝新铁路重新运行的时候
celebrate the re-opening of the new rail line.
我们不谈谈刚才发生的事吗
Are we not gonna talk about what just happened?
那家伙用手一碰  那个人就死了
That dude just killed that guy by touching him.
等等  对手是个超能力者吗
Wait, we're dealing with a metahuman?
我们的麻烦还不够多吗
Like we didn't have enough problems?
他不是超能力者
He wasn't a metahuman.
奥利弗  那个人的行为是超自然的
Oliver, what that man did was not natural.
我知道  是很神秘
I know. It was mystical.
你凭什么这么确定
How can you be so sure?
因为我见过一些事
Because I've seen things.
有些事连科学都无法解释
There's things that can't be explained, even by science.
我想你不打算告诉我们
I suppose you aren't going to tell us
你见过什么事了  奥利弗
about these things you've seen, Oliver.
我们得集中精力  找到集束炸弹
We need to focus on finding the cluster bombs.
能激活定位装置吗
Can you activate the GPS?
可以  但我敢肯定
Eventually. But I'm pretty sure
到那时火车站已经被炸飞了
the train station's gonna be blown up by then.
好吧  那我们这次用老办法
Fine. So we do this the old-fashioned way.
这就是老办法
So this is the old-fashioned way?
我们能谈谈昨晚的事吗
Can we maybe discuss last night?
很神奇  对不对
It's pretty amazing, right?
但你怎么会愿意放弃这种刺激呢
But how could you ever want to give up that rush?
其实很简单
Extremely easily.
重点不在这
It's--it's not what I'm talking about.
你当时好像有点失控
You seemed a little out of control.
说这话的居然是
This coming from the guy
一贯把罪犯当成靶子练射击的人
who used to use criminals as target practice.
我对你这五个月的进步刮目相看
I'm amazed by how far you've come in 5 months,
我也很清楚这样的生活充满暴力
and I'm under no illusions that this isn't a violent life.
我只是想让你记住  我们和他们的区别
I just, I want you to remember that it's restraint
在于克制
separating us from them.
你回来才多久  24小时
Well, you've managed to be back, what, 24 hours
就开始教训我了
before giving me a lecture.
这下我欠劳蕾尔50美元了
Think I owe Laurel 50 bucks.
我是认真的
I'm being serious.
这种情况持续多久了
How long has this been going on for?
什么情况也没有
Nothing is going on.
好吧  我只是成了一个更好的斗士
Ok, I've just--just become a better fighter.
好的斗士  打斗时能够自我控制
A better fighter remains in control when they fight.
你没事吧
Is everything ok?
有事
It's not ok.
我哥哥似乎总是要管我
My brother can't seem to stay out of my business.
有线索吗
Any luck?
没有
No.
你看西娅是不是不太正常
Does Thea seem a little off to you?
她没事
No, she's fine.
只是有点好斗罢了
Just a little too aggressive maybe.
你忘了你刚开始也这样
Remember, you were the same way when you started out.
我看你听了我对于隐藏身份的建议
Saw that you took my advice on the identity concealment.
奥利弗  你在干什么
Oliver, man, what are we doing?
假装一切都正常
Pretending everything's normal,
我们也都正常吗
that we are normal?
我在想办法融入
I'm looking for a way in.
想到你信任马尔科姆·梅林多过信任我
I was furious to think that you trusted
我就怒不可遏
Malcolm Merlyn more than you trust me.
但后来我意识到我不是在生你的气
But then I realized that I'm not angry at you,
而是生我自己的气  因为很显然
I'm angry at myself for thinking you're someone
我看错你了
that you clearly aren't.
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what that means.
奥利弗  我们经历了这么多
Oliver, after everything we've been through, man,
我想不通你为什么不信任我
I couldn't fathom why you didn't trust me.
但后来我意识到  你就是做不到
But then I realized you couldn't.
你不是这样的人
It's not who you are.
你不信任  不爱任何人
You don't trust. You don't love.
你能骗过拉斯  加入刺客联盟
You were able to fool Ra's and join the League
是因为你的内心跟他们一样黑暗
because inside you are every bit as dark as they are.
谢谢你来一趟
Thank you for coming.
处理炸弹威胁也是
Responding to a bomb threat's kind of
星城警局的职责
in the SCPD job description.
你知道我不是这意思  很高兴我们能合作
You know what I mean. I'm glad we're working together.
看来最近你跟不少人合作
It seems like you're working with a lot of people these days.
这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
-失陪一会  -爸
- Excuse me. - Dad.
浪子绿箭回来了
Prodigal Arrow returns.
兰斯队长
Captain Lance.
我就知道昨晚
I thought that was you last night,
那个戴着兜帽的人是你  跟以前一样
some mask over your head. Felt like old times.
我只是想出份力
Only trying to help.
若是如此  你就不会回来了
That were true, you wouldn't have come back.
从你戴上兜帽那刻起
This town started going to crap
这座城市就开始麻烦四起
the moment you put on that hood.
你把各种疯狂的事带到我们生活中
You brought madness into all of our lives,
因为你这个恶魔  唤起了更多的恶魔
and the monster you were inspired monsters.
也许
Maybe.
但我已经不再是恶魔了
But I'm not a monster anymore.
那你是什么
Then what are you?
睡得好吗
Nice nap?
我不是在打盹  我是被人下药了
I wasn't napping. I was drugged.
沃勒在哪
Where's Waller?
回到海滨城  睡觉醒酒了
Back in Coast City sleeping off the scotch.
叫醒她
Wake her up.
我要知道我来这干什么
I want to know what I'm doing here.
沃勒指挥官叫我感谢你
Director Waller has asked me
同意参与这次任务
to thank you for agreeing to take on this mission.
我没同意参与任何...
I didn't agree to take on any--
抱歉  我们时间不多
Sorry. We're in a bit of a clock here.
现在你要准备下机
Now, you're getting off this plane.
你可以背上降落伞跳下去
You can do that with a chute on your back
或由我一枪打爆你的头  你决定
or a bullet in your head. Your call.
沃勒为什么要这么做
Why is Waller doing this?
看来她喜欢你
Guess she likes you.
没想到沃勒也会喜欢人
I didn't think Waller could like anybody.
而且你了解地形
Plus, you know the terrain.
什么地形
What terrain?
你的工作就是要潜入该区域
Your job is to infiltrate the area,
评估威胁性  然后上报
assess the threat, and report back.
你的背包里有高级加密通讯设备
You have AES-encrypted communication gear in your pack.
根据我们的情报
Now, according to our intel,
你的目标也许有雷达监测
your target may be radar capable,
所以你要高跳低开进入
so you'll have to HALO in.
当你觉得你快失控时
So when you think you're about to splat,
再拉开你的伞
only then do you pull the shoot.
等等  那是...
Wait, is that--
怎么一脸无精打采的样子
Uh-oh. You have mopey face.
是在担心过了五个月的逍遥日子
Were you worried after 5 months of happiness
再也没法像以前那么神勇了吗
that you weren't going to be able to make it anymore?
我碰到了兰斯
I ran into Lance.
他因为想念你  所以拥抱你了吗
And he gave you a hug because he missed you?
好吧  不只是兰斯
Yeah, well, it's not just Lance.
还有西娅  西娅不太对劲
Thea. There is something wrong with Thea.
她和狄格尔都不要我帮忙
She doesn't want my help and neither does Diggle.
我们就不该回来
We should never have come back here.
那走吧  我们回家吧
Let's go. Let's go home.
你不想回家
You don't want to go home.
我爱我们的新家
I love our new home.
我爱你
And I love you.
可我也爱这里
But I also love it here,
你不能说你不爱
and you can't honestly tell me that you don't.
没错  我当然想念这里的某些方面
Yeah, no, of course I miss aspects of it.
有目标的感觉  帮助他人的理念
The sense of purpose, the idea of helping people.
可兰斯说得对
But Lance was right.
哪一方面
About what?
几个月前他告诉我
A few months ago he told me
我从那个小岛带回来的
that all I brought back from the island
只有伤痛  不幸和黑暗
was pain, misery, and darkness.
我当然知道我们回来的那一刻
Of course I knew that the moment we came back here,
那股黑暗就等着我
that darkness would be waiting for me.
那他错了  错得很离谱
Well, he's wrong. Dead wrong.
你没有把那种黑暗从炼狱带回来
You didn't bring the darkness back with you from Lian Yu.
但是  费利西蒂  我要告诉你
But, Felicity, I'm telling you that
我知道的对抗黑暗的唯一方法
the only way I know how to fight the darkness
就是融入黑暗中  所以我才选择离开
is to be darkness. That is why I left.
我不想再做那种人了
And I don't want to be that type of person anymore.
也许你只是需要做个不一样的人
Maybe you just need to be a different kind of person.
你现在不再是孤身作战
And you're not doing this alone anymore.
火车站那什么都没有
Train station was a bust.
月台上  铁轨上
No incendiaries on the platform,
或是任何一辆列车里都没有燃烧弹
on the tracks, or inside any of the trains.
嗯  可如果炸弹不在车站
Yeah, but if there's no bomb in the station,
那他们要怎么实施爆炸
then how did they expect to blow it up?
你并没把那种黑暗带回来
You didn't bring the darkness here.
炸弹不在车站里
The bombs aren't at the station
因为他们正带着炸弹进去
because they're bringing them in.
在列车上
On a train.
重开仪式是什么时候
When's the reopening ceremony scheduled for?
9点58分  为了配合第一辆
9:58, to coincide with the arrival
从中城开来的高速列车
of the first high speed train from Central City.
穿上装备吧
Let's suit up.
你也该穿上装备
You should suit up, too.
什么
What?
开近点
Get me closer.
我尽量
I'm trying.
大家赶快离开
Everybody get out of here.
这里有危险
It's not safe.
闪开  闪开  闪开
Out of the way, out of the way, out of the way.
你真有力
Whoa. You're really strong.
快走
Go.
星城警察
This is SCPD.
大家快速安静地撤离车站
Everyone quickly and quietly evacuate the station.
大家冷静地走向出口  不要紧张
Everyone move calmly towards the exits. Calmly.
列车十分钟后到达
The train is 10 minutes out.
离最稳妥的爆炸半径范围只剩六分钟
6 minutes till safest blast radius.
报告情况
Situation report.
斯莱特先生
Mr. Slater.
抱歉  他得提前下车了
Sorry. He had to get off at an earlier stop.
你不可能是绿箭  他死了  你是谁
You can't be the Arrow, he died. So who are you?
你很快就知道了
You're about to find out.
让列车停下
Stop the train.
我不想停
No, I don't want to.
即使我愿意  我也不能
Even if I did, I couldn't.
二十英里之前我就破坏了刹车系统
I destroyed the braking system 20 miles ago.
为了毁掉火车站  不惜一死吗
Willing to die to destroy a train station?
不  那太可笑了
No, that would be ridiculous.
那你打算怎么逃离火车
Then how are you planning on getting off the train?
你不知道我是谁  对吗
Oh, you don't know who I am, do you?
我是达米恩·达克
I'm Damien Darhk.
你就这点能耐吗
Is that all you got?
你跟绿箭挺像的
It seems you've much in common with the Arrow.
你们都是死人了
You're both dead.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们必须让火车停下
We need to stop the train.
有什么主意吗
Got any ideas?
有  把它炸了
Yeah, blow it up.
现在你打算怎么称呼自己
So what are you gonna call yourself now?
大家都以为罗伊是绿箭
Everybody thinks Roy was the Arrow.
如果他回常春藤镇  他就不需要代号
He won't need a code name if he's headed back to Ivy Town.
好吧  那么我想我需要一个代号
Well, then I guess I need a code name.
费利西蒂和我都很想念这些
Felicity and I, we have missed this.
我们想念你们所有人
We've missed all of you.
而且这座城市比我们想象的更糟
And the city is far worse off than we thought.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
领导幽灵的是达米恩·达克
The man leading The Ghosts is Damian Darhk.
达克几个月前离开了星城
Darhk left Star City months ago.
他为什么要回来
Why would he come back?
你从拉斯那里掌握到
Did Ra's tell you anything about Darhk
能洞悉达克的计划的信息吗
that would give us any idea about his agenda?
他说达米恩·达克有一个蜂群的特工
He said that Damian Darhk had a hive of operatives
为他效力
at his disposal.
蜂群
A hive?
这是他说的原话吗
That was the exact word he used?
是的  怎么了
Yes. Why?
你听说过吗
Does it mean something to you?
谁想杀安迪
Who would want to kill Andy?
不知道他们的名字  只有化名
Don't know their names, just an alias.
蜂群
Hive.
没有
No.
完全没听过
No, nothing.
-你还好吗  -没事
- You all right? - Yeah, yeah.
我没事  兄弟  我只是累了
I'm fine, man. I'm just beat.
另外我还有个宝贝女儿等我回去哄睡觉 呢
Plus, I have a little girl to tuck in.
约翰
John.
听着  我
Listen, I'm, um,
我不在状态  奥利弗
I'm not quite there yet, Oliver,
所以现在还是不要说了
so let's not do this right now.
我知道  我理解
No, I know. I get it.
但是有件事我们必须去做
But there is something we do need to do.
星城警局
-队长  有个新问题  -真的吗
- Captain, new problem. - Seriously?
有人黑进了紧急播报系统
Someone's hacked into the emergency broadcast system.
他们已经控制了所有的电视台
They've taken over all the networks.
六个月前  绿箭死了
6 months ago, the Arrow died.
但他的理念没有消逝
But what he stood for didn't.
由戴着他的兜帽的英雄们延续下去
It lived on in the heroes who took up his mantle.
那些相信这座城市
People who believe that this city
不应该陷入绝望的人们
should never descend into hopelessness.
相信虽然光明中充满了黑暗
Who believe although light is full of darkness,
但黑暗是找到光明的关键
that darkness can be the key to find light.
今晚  我宣布
And tonight, I am declaring my intention
将会和他们站在一起
to stand with them,
为这座城市而战
to fight for this city,
做到之前绿箭从没有做到的
to be the symbol of hope
成为这座城的希望象征
that the Arrow never was.
我是
I am
绿箭侠
the Green Arrow.
你是谁
Who are you?
回答我
Answer me.
[咒语]
Kanjigar septum vohnostrum.
你有客人
You have a visitor.
很抱歉弄伤你的胳膊
Sorry about the arm.
让你受点小伤  以防止
Unnecessary subterfuge to prevent anyone
任何人怀疑你参与了蜂巢
from suspecting your involvement with the Hive.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我有点失望
Well, I'm a little disappointed
火车站并没有变成一堆灰烬
the train station isn't a smoldering pile of ash.
我没有  大屠杀  杀戮无辜者
I'm not. Mass murder, killing innocents.
我当初没答应做这些
I didn't sign up for this.
你答应听从我的指令
You signed up to follow my instructions,
执行我的意愿
to do my will.
我想知道关于这个绿箭侠的所有事
I want to know everything about this Green Arrow,
他住在哪  他的爱人是谁
where he lives, and who he loves,
我希望等我的同伴到来的时候
and I want him off the boards by the time
他已经不在了
my associates arrive.
如果我不帮你呢
And if I don't help you?
那我会很震惊
Well, then I would be surprised.
因为我想我已经很明确地表示过
'Cause I think I made it abundantly clear
你别无选择
you don't have a choice.
这个住处太棒了  使我对取代西娅
So my guilt for displacing Thea
成为这里的女主人的事
is only slightly outweighed
不再那么内疚了
by how amazing this place is.
事实上  过去的几个月
Thea's actually been living with Laurel
西娅和劳蕾尔住在一起
for the past few months.
拉斯就在那里刺伤了她
Ra's stabbed her right over there.
我们可以买个小地毯
We can get a rug.
我不想让你失望
You know, I'd hate to disappoint you,
但那个演讲能给人带来希望
but that speech is pretty hopeful.
那为什么会让我失望
Why would that disappoint me?
你知道当你说你不知道
Oh, you know how you said you didn't know
如何做一个没有黑暗面的英雄
how to be a hero without the darkness?
我知道你有多讨厌犯错误
And I know how you hate being wrong.
六个月后
抱歉我错过了葬礼
Sorry I missed the funeral.
-极速  -是的
- Zoom? - Yeah.
曾经我会以为这是我的错
There was a time I would have thought this was my fault,
是我把黑暗带给了大家
that I brought this darkness upon us.
现在我知道这不是我的错
Now I know it's not my fault.
这是我的责任
It's my responsibility.
做什么的责任
Responsibility to do what?
来结束它
To end it.
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
有什么我能做的吗
Is there anything I can do?
让我单独待一会
I want to be left alone.
好吧
Ok.